LUIS HENRIQUE VALGOI

Brazilian | 24 years old luisvalgoi.github.io



PERSONAL SUMMARY

Passionate about Software Engineering Principles, Javascript and User Interface with more than 7 years in the development area. With strong soft & presentation skills, always looking for transparency in relationships, knowledge spreading, initiatives leadership and new challenges.

EDUCATION

ASSOCIATE DEGREE (FEB 2016 – DEC 2020) - UNISINOS: Systems and Analysis Development Object-oriented programming, web development, software engineering, software quality, project management and more.

TECHNICAL COURSE (MAR 2010 – NOV 2014) - IFSUL: Technical Education in Software Development High School integrated with technical education in software development such as ANDROID, JAVA, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript and more.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER (JAN 2021 – UNTIL NOW) - Avenue Code

Working to define and shape new design systems and internal customer frameworks to better increase the productivity of other developers using TDD and several other best practices. Also acting in architecting different projects according to the business requirement of the specific line of business.

SPECIALIST FRONTEND DEVELOPER (MAR 2018 – DEC 2020) - SAP Labs Latin America

Responsible for architectural decisions related to frontend, such as estimative, mentoring, training and innovative decisions such as first React usage at IBSO LOB. Also focused on activities related to User Experience and User Interface, such as Wireframe and MockUps design.

.NET DEVELOPER (MAY 2016 - OCT 2016) - HCL Technologies

Member of AppTeam at HCL working directly in development of front-end and back-end ePharma requirements and project with DDD pattern using C#, ExtUS, Oracle PL/SQL and SCRUM.

.NET ANALYST DEVELOPER (MAR 2015 – MAY 2016) - ACCERA Supply and Sales Empowered

Development and maintenance of Web systems, specifics client's workflows and bug fixes using C#, HTML5, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript, also, main responsible developer during the 'Contenção' project in the 'Canal Direto' working directly with AWS, Redshift and SQL Server.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Methodologies: SCRUM & Extreme Programming (XP) and Test Driven Design (TDD).

Database: Oracle SQL, SQL Server, Amazon Redshift and SAP HANA.

Front-End: JavaScript, React, RTL, Enzyme, Jest, Context API, Redux, Saga, NextJS, CSS3 and HTML5.

Design Systems: Bootstrap, Tailwind, UI5 WebComponents and Material Design.

Back-End: ODATA, REST, Node.js, C#, JAVA, Python and SAP HANA XS.

Platforms: Amazon Web Service and SAP Cloud Platform.

PROJECTS

WECOMMUNITY – WECONNECT (Frontend Architect)

WeCommunity is a WeConnect platform which manages the status of the self-registered women-owned businesses application through automatic emails. In addition, member buyers and certified women-owned businesses will be able to post simple solicitations. This helps the women-owned businesses to grow and connect with each other and with member buyers.

VISIT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (Analyst | Architect | Full Stack & Lead Developer)

Visit Management System (old LCCApp) is a SAP global solution that manages all info and its process steps regarding some customer visits to some SAP Location. The application creates an easy end-to-end way between requestor (i.e. Account Executives) and approver (i.e. Labs Customer Center Employees) to open, check, manage, approve and guide the customer about their possibilities at the location.

FAST FOOD CHAIN MAINTENANCE (Front-End Lead Developer | Presenter at SAP Forum Brazil)

The SAP-Burger King prototype is an intelligent maintenance system that uses SAP Leonardo capabilities to allow a more proactive and efficient maintenance operation for Burger King. It was selected as project winner and received 3/4 project awards (Design, Internet of Things Technology and Machine Learning).

FOOD MANAGER APP (Product Owner | Analyst | Architect | Lead Developer)

Food Manager is an Android application developed as a final project during High School for entrepreneurs, which has a small or medium-sized food establishment, aimed at improving the agility of the service, inventory management and better control in general through its functionalities.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

AGILE SOFTWARE ENGINEER TRAINER (2019 - Walldorf)

Trainer certification for participating in more than 45 hours of Training the Trainer of the Agile Software Engineer for JavaScript occurred at SAP SE - Walldorf covering Clean Code, Refactoring, TDD, Test Isolation, Design Patterns & more.

DESIGN THINKING COACH (2019)

More than 64 hours of Design Thinking Training as part of the SAP User Experience & SAP Development Learning. Being separated in 3 different subjects, the curriculum covers from the beginning to mastering all important aspects of a DT Coach. Included modules were: Method Camp, Coaching Camp and Boost Camp.

LABS CUSTOMER CENTER AWARD (Visit Management System)

Recognition award for build and take the development lead of the Labs Customer Center App (the Visit Management System) improving Labs Customer Center efficiency and turning into a 'Run Simple' process.

CHAMPION OF SAP LABS LATIN AMERICA INNOWEEKS 2017 (Fast Food Chain Maintenance)

Member of the development team (front-end lead) in the SAP Labs Latin America InnoWeeks 2017, which was responsible for implementing a prototype called 'Fast Food Chain Maintenance' which is an intelligent maintenance system that uses SAP Leonardo capabilities to allow a more proactive and efficient maintenance operation for Burger King. The project won the following awards: "InnoWeeks 2017 Design Award", "InnoWeeks 2017 Internet of Things Technology Award" and "InnoWeeks 2017 Machine Learning Award".

THE IMPORTANCE OF TECHNOLOGY IN RESTAURANTS (Food Manager App)

In the 8th Mocitec Edition, performed in September / 2014 at Charqueadas-RS, the Food Manager App combined to a Scientific Article won the "Outstanding Project in IT Area".